<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Be +</string>
    <string name="title_get_blood">Get Blood</string>
    <string name="title_donate_blood">Donate Blood</string>
    <string name="title_first_aid">First Aid</string>
    <string name="name_of_disease">Name of disease</string>
    <string-array name="state">
        <item>Madhya Pradesh</item>
        <item>Uttar Pradesh</item>
        <item>Punjab</item>
        <item>Bihar</item>
        <item>Gujrat</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="city">
        <item>Gwalior</item>
        <item>Delhi</item>
        <item>Lucknow</item>
        <item>Bengaluru</item>
        <item>Amritsar</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="blood_group">
        <item>A+</item>
        <item>A-</item>
        <item>B+</item>
        <item>B-</item>
        <item>O+</item>
        <item>O-</item>
        <item>AB+</item>
        <item>AB-</item>

    </string-array>


    <string name="first_aid">"Select your emergency and follow the steps:"</string>


    <string-array name="donors_guidelines">
        <item>Eligibilities</item>
        <item>Non-Eligibilities</item>
        <item>Preparation</item>
        <item>Post Donation Care</item>
        <item>How to Relieve?</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="first_aid_diseases">
        <item>Burns and Scalds</item>
        <item>Bites and Stings</item>
        <item>Drowning</item>
        <item>Electrical Burn</item>
        <item>Fainting</item>
        <item>Fever</item>
        <item>Fracture - Closed</item>
        <item>Fracture - Open</item>
        <item>Foreign Objects in the Eyes</item>
        <item>Heart Attack</item>
        <item>Nose Bleed</item>
        <item>Seizerus/Epilepsy</item>
        <item>Severe External Bleeding</item>
        <item>Swallowed Poisons</item>
        <item>Vommiting and Diarrhea</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="eligibilities">\n\n1. Any donor, who is healthy, fit and not suffering from any transmittable diseases can donate blood.
        \n\n2. Donor must be 18 -60 years age and having a minimum weight of 50Kg can donate blood.
        \n\n3. Donor’s Hemoglobin level is 12.5% minimum.
        \n\n4. A donor can again donate blood after 3 months of your last donation of blood.
        \n\n5. Pulse rate must be between 50 to 100mm without any irregularities.
        \n\n6. BP Diastolic 50 to 100 mm Hg and Systolic 100 to 180 mm Hg.
        \n\n7. Body temperature should be normal and oral temperature should not exceed 37.5 degree Celsius.\n\n</string>

    <string name="nonEligibilities">\n\n1. Donors should not suffer from Cardiac arrest, hypertension, kidney alignments, epilepsy or diabetics.
        \n\n2. Ladies with a bad miscarriage should avoid donating blood for the next 6 months.
        \n\n3. If donor already donated blood or have been treated for malaria within the last three months.
        \n\n4. If donor undergone any immunization within the past one month.
        \n\n5. If donor consumed alcohol within the last 24 hours.
        \n\n6. If you are HIV+.
        \n\n7. If donor had a dental work for next 24 hours and wait for one month if donor had a major dental procedure.\n\n</string>

    <string name="preparation">\n\n1. Prepare yourself by having enough fruit juice and water in the night and morning before you donate blood.
        \n\n2. Avoid donating blood in empty stomach. Eat three hours before you donate blood. Avoid fatty foods. Eat food which
        is rich in iron such as whole grains, eggs, and beef, and spinach, leafy vegetables, orange and citrus.
        \n\n3. Don’t consume Alcohol or caffeine beverages before donating blood.
        \n\n4. Avoid donating blood for 6 months if you had any major surgery.\n\n</string>

    <string name="postDonationCare">\n\n1. Have some rest 5 to 20 minutes after donation. Do not drive after donation of blood.
        \n\n2. Have some snacks and juice with high sugar content which will help to rejuvenate the blood sugar back up.
        \n\n3. Have a good meal with high protein content such as Chicken, Beef etc,.
        \n\n4. Do not consume Alcohol for 8 hours after donation of blood.
        \n\n5. Avoid going for a heavy body works such as gym, dancing, running etc at least for next one day.\n\n</string>

    <string name="howToRelieve">\n\nWhile you are being needled to take blood, relax to the maximum, have a deep breath.
        There will be little pain or no pain.\n
        Try to distract yourself from the process by having a chewing gum.
        Listen to some music or watch some entertaining TV program.\n\n</string>


    <string name="SEVERE_EXTERNAL_BLEEDING" translatable="false">\n1. Remove or cut clothing as necessary to expose the wound.\n
    \n2. Apply direct pressure over the wound with your fingers using a sterile dressing or clean, gauze pad. If you do not have a
dressing, ask the casualty to apply direct pressure himself. If there is an object in the wound, apply pressure on either side of the
object (opposite).\n
    \n3. Maintain direct pressure on the wound to control bleeding. Raise and support the injured limb above the level of the
        casualty’s heart to reduce blood loss.\n\n
    \n<b>Caution:</b>\n Do not allow the casualty to eat or drink because ananesthetic may be needed.\nIf the casualty loses consciousness
        and is not breathing normally, begin CPR with chest compressions.\n</string>

    <string name="BURNS_AND_SCALDS">\n1. Start cooling the burn as soon as possible after the injury occurred for at least ten minutes.
        Watch for signs of breathing difficulty. Do not overcool the casualty because you may lower the body temperature to a dangerous level. This is a particular hazard for babies and elderly people.\n
    \n2. Do not touch or otherwise interfere with the burn. Do not remove clothing that is stuck to the burn.\n
        \n3. When the burn is cooled, cover the injured area with plastic wrap to protect it from infection.
    \n</string>
    <string name="BITES_AND_STINGS">\n1. Gently clean the area around the splinter with soap and warm water.\n
    \n2. Hold the tweezers close to draw the splinter out in the end for a better grip.
        Grasp the splinter with tweezers as close to the skin as possible.\n
    \n3. Draw the splinter out in a straight line at the same angle that it went into the skin; make sure it does not break.\n
    \n4. Carefully squeeze the wound to encourage a little bleeding. This will help flush out any remaining dirt.\n
        \n5. Wash again with soap and water. Clean and dry the wound and cover with a dressing.
    \n</string>

    <string name="HEART_ATTACK" translatable="false">\n1. Call 102 for emergency help. Tell the dispatcher that you suspect a heart attack.
        If the casualty asks you to do so, call his own doctor too.\n
    \n2. Make the casualty as comfortable as possibleto ease the strain on his heart. A half-sitting position, with his head and
        shoulders supported and his knees bent, is often best.Place cushions behind him and under his knees.\n
    \n3. Assist the casualty to take up to one full-dose adult aspirin tablet (325 mg).If the casualty has angina medication,
such as tablets or a pump-action or aerosol spray, let him administer it; help him if necessary.\n
\n4. Encourage him to rest.Monitor and record vital signs—level of response, breathing, and pulse,while waiting for help. Stay
calm to avoid undue stress.\n</string>
    <string name="DROWNING">\n1. If you have rescued the casualty from the water, help him lie down on a rug or coat with his head
        lower than the rest of the body so that water can drain from his mouth. This reduces the risk of inhaling water.\n
\n2. Treat the casualty for hypothermia; replace wet clothing with dry clothes if possible and cover him with dry blankets or coats.\n
        If the casualty is fully conscious, give him a warm drink.\n
        \n3.If the casualty is unconscious and you are on your own, give CPR for two  minutes before you call 102 for emergency help.\n
        \n4. If an unconscious casualty starts to breathe,treat him for hypothermia by covering him with warm clothes and blankets.
        Monitor and record vital signs—breathing, pulse and level of response until help arrives.\n</string>
    <string name="FEVER">\n1. Keep casualty cool and comfortable preferably in bed with a light covering.\n
\n2.Give him plenty of cool drinks to replace body fluids lost through sweating.\n
        \n3. If the person appears distressed or ill, he/she may have the recommended dose of acetaminophen syrup (not aspirin).
An adult may take the recommended dose of acetaminophen or ibuprofen, or his own pain relievers.\n
        \n4. Monitor and record a casualty’s vital signs—level of response, breathing, pulse, and temperature until he/she recovers.\n
        \n\n<b>Caution: </b> Do not give aspirin to any person under 16 years of age.
    \n</string>

    <string name="FRACTURES_CLOSED">\n1. Advise the casualty to keep still. Support the joints above and below the injury with your hands
        until it is immobilized with a sling or bandages, in the position in which it is found.\n
    \n2. Place padding around the injury for extra support. Take or send the casualty to the hospital; a casualty with an arm
        injury may be transported by car; call 102 for emergency help for a leg injury.\n
        \n3. For firmer support and/or if removal to the hospital is likely to be delayed,
        secure the injured part to an unaffected part of the body. For upper limb fractures,
        immobilize the arm with a sling. For lower limb fractures, move the uninjured leg to the
        injured one and secure with broad-fold bandages. Always tie knots on the uninjured side.\n
        \n4. Treat for shock if necessary. Do not raise an injured leg. Elevate an uninjured limb
        if shock is present. Monitor and record vital signs while waiting for help. Check the
        circulation beyond a sling or bandage every ten minutes.If the circulation is impaired,
        loosen the bandages.\n</string>
    <string name="FRACTURES_OPEN">
        \n1. Cover the wound with a sterile dressing or large, clean, gauze
pad. Apply pressure around the injury to control bleeding ; be careful not to press on a
        protruding bone.\n
        \n2. Carefully place a sterile wound dressing or more clean padding over and around the
        dressing.\n
        \n3. Secure the dressing and padding with a bandage. Bandage firmly, but not so tightly
        that it impairs the circulation beyond  the bandage.\n
        \n4. Immobilize the injured part as for a closed fracture, and arrange to transport the
        casualty to the hospital.\n
        \n5. Treat the casualty for shock if necessary. Do not raise the injured leg. Monitor and
        record vital signs—level of response, breathing, and pulse while waiting for help to
        arrive. Check the circulation beyond the bandage every ten minutes. If the circulation
        is impaired, loosen the bandages.
    \n</string>

    <string name="ELECTRICAL_BURN">\n1. Make sure that contact with the electrical source is
        broken before you touch the casualty.\n
        \n2. Flood the injury with cold water (at the entry and exit points if both are present)
        for at least ten minutes or until pain is relieved. If water is not available, any cold,
        harmless liquid can be used.\n
        \n3. Gently remove any jewelry, watches, belts, or constricting clothing from the
        injured area before it begins to swell. Do not touch the burn.\n
        \n4. When the burn is cooled, place a clean plastic bag over a burn on a foot or hand,
        taping the bag loosely in place (attach tape to the bag, not the skin). Or, cover
        the burn with plastic wrap, laying it along the length of the limb so that it does not become too tight. If neither is
available, use a sterile dressing or a clean gauze pad loosely.

    \n</string>
    <string name="SEIZURES" translatable="false">\n1. Make space around the casualty, and ask bystanders to move away. Remove potentially dangerous
        items, such as hot drinks and sharp objects. Note the time that the seizure started.\n
\n2. Protect the casualty’s head from objects nearby; place soft padding such as rolled towels underneath or around his neck if
        possible. Loosen tight clothing around his neck if necessary.\n
    \n3. When the convulsive movements have ceased, open the casualty’s airway and check breathing. If he is breathing, place
        him in the recovery position.
        \n\n4. Monitor and record his vital signs—level of response, breathing, and pulse until he/she recovers. Make a note of how
        long the seizure lasted.
    \n</string>

    <string name="NOSEBLEED" translatable="false">\n<i>* Bleeding from the nose most commonly occurs when tiny blood vessels inside the nostrils are
        ruptured, either by a blow to the nose, or as a result of sneezing, picking, or blowing the nose. </i>\n\n
        <i>** Do not let the casualty tip his head back because blood may then run down the throat andinduce vomiting.</i>\n
        \n1. Tell the casualty to sit down and tilt his head forward to allow the blood to drain from the
nostrils. Ask him to breathe through his mouth (this will have a calming effect) and to pinch the soft part of his nose for
        up to ten minutes, holding constant pressure. Reassure and help him if necessary.\n
\n2. Advise the casualty not to speak, swallow, cough, spit, or sniff since this may disturb blood clots that have formed in the
        nose. Give hima clean cloth or tissue to mop up any dribbling.\n
        \n3. After ten minutes, tell the casualty torelease the pressure. If the bleeding hasnot stopped, tell him to reapply
        the pressurefor two further periods of ten minutes.\n
        \n4. Advise him to rest quietly for a few hours. Tell him to avoid exertion and, in particular, not to blow his nose,
        because thiscould disturb any clots.
\n</string>


    <string name="FOREIGN_OBJECT_IN_THE_EYE">\n1. Advise the casualty not to rub his/her eye. Ask him/her to sit down facing a light.\n
    \n2. Stand beside, or just behind, the casualty. Gently separate her eyelids with your thumbs or finger and thumb. Ask
her to look right, left, up, and down. Examine every part of her eye as she does this.\n
        \n3. If you can see a foreign object on the white of the eye, wash it out by pouring clean water from a glass or pitcher,
        or by using a sterile eyewash if you have one. Put a towel around the casualty’s shoulders. Hold her eye open and pour
        the water from the inner corner so that it drains onto the towel.\n
        \n4. If this is unsuccessful, try lifting the object off with a moist swab or the damp corner of a clean handkerchief
        or tissue. If you still cannot remove the object, seek medical help.\n</string>

    <string name="VOMITING_AND_DIARRHEA" translatable="false">\n1. Reassure the casualty if she is vomiting and give her a warm damp cloth to wipe her
        face.\n
\n2. Help her sit down and when the vomiting stops give her water or unsweetened fruit juice to sip slowly and often.\n
\n3. When the casualty is hungry again, advise  her to eat easily digested foods such as pasta, bread, or potatoes for the first
        24 hours\n
        \n4. If the vomiting and/or diarrhea are severe, or the casualty develops chest pain, difficulty breathing, or severe
        abdominal pain, take or arrange to send him/her to the hospital. If the casualty becomes lightheaded or dizzy,
        treat for fainting. \n</string>

    <string name="SWALLOWED_POISONS">\n1. If the casualty is conscious, ask her what she has swallowed, and  if possible how much
        and when. Look for clues—for example, poisonous plants, berries or empty containers. Try to reassure her.\n
    \n2. Call for help,Give the dispatcher  as much information as possible about the poison. This information will help the
        medical team treat the casualty.\n
        \n3. Monitor and record the casualty’s vital signs while waiting for help to arrive. Keep samples of any vomited material.
Give these samples, containers, and any others clues to the emergency services.\n\n
        \n<i>* If the casualty’s lips are burned by corrosive substances, give him frequent sips of cold milk or water while waiting
            for help to arrive.\n</i>

    </string>

    <string name="FAINTING">\n1. When a casualty feels  faint, advise him to lie down. Kneel down, raise his legs, supporting
        his ankles on your shoulders to improve blood flow to the brain. Watch his face for signs of recovery.\n
    \n2. Make sure that the casualty has plenty of fresh air; ask someone to open a window if you are indoors. In addition, ask
any bystanders to stand clear. He may be more comfortable  if his knees are bent.\n
    \n3. As the casualty recovers, reassure him and help him  sit up gradually. If he starts to feel faint again, advise him to
lie down once again, and raise and support his legs until he recovers fully.
    \n</string>
    <string name="dialog_get_blood">May you get the required blood.\nPlease spread
        awareness among people to come forward for
    Blood Donation, it can save many lives.</string>
    <string name="dialog_donate_blood">Every drop of Blood counts!\nIf you’re a blood donor, you’re a hero to someone, somewhere,
        who received your gracious gift of life.</string>
    <string name="select_the_credentials">Select the credentials:</string>
    <string name="list_blood_bank">The requested Blood Group can be found at these Blood Banks
        with indicative Quantities:</string>
    <string name="sign_out">Sign Out</string>
    <string name="select_problem">Select Problem !</string>
    <string name="disease_detail">Description</string>
    <string name="blood_banks">Blood Banks</string>
    <string name="details">Details</string>
    <string name="donors_guidelines">Donors Guidelines</string>
    <string name="agreement">I\'m eligible and Wish to Donate</string>
    <string name="guideline_head">Before you Donate Blood, you need to know Donors Guidelines:</string>

</resources>
